《女子监狱》
第二季第十三集
大人物们
The big guns.
穿身西装就把自己当老大了
Think they're so boss 'cause they wear suits.
蠢透的特别调查处  他们来这干什么
Stupid SIS. Why are they even here?
一起刺伤  紧接着一起重物袭击
Well, a stabbing and a slocking back-to-back...
这里要变成整死人的赖克斯岛监狱了
It's turned into fucking Rikers around here.
他们会像审犯人一样拷问狱警
You know they're gonna grill the COs as hard as the inmates.
那群混蛋都巴不得逮住咱们
Those dicks are all dying to nail us.
先生们  早上好
Gentlemen, good morning.
欢迎来到利奇菲尔德  希望你们过得愉快
Welcome to Litchfield. Enjoy your stay.
马屁精
Kiss ass.
先生们  很高兴见到你们
Gentlemen, nice to see you.
我是乔・卡普托队长
Captain Joe Caputo.
-早  -早
- Morning. - Morning.
我想在你们开始调查之前
Uh, I thought we could meet in my office
咱们可以先在我办公室见个面
and go over the details of the incident
重温一下事故的细节
before you begin your investigation.
我们要向菲格罗亚女士报到
Well, we report to Miss Figueroa.
我觉得我能提供更多信息
Right, well, I believe I can provide more information.
菲格罗亚女士那晚不在监狱
Miss Figueroa wasn't on campus that evening.
我们接到指示  要单独与她会面
We have instructions to meet with her exclusively.
到时候  我们会连同其他狱警一起
We'll interview you along with the other COs
跟你面谈
when the time comes.
好  我带你们去她办公室
Sure, sure. I'll show you to her office.
最好再来杯咖啡
Some coffee would be great, too.
加奶  两包糖
Light. Two sugars.
马车轻轻摇晃
Swing low
这种处罚还算轻的了
Guess it could be worse.
想当年
Back in the day,
他们会把咱们发配到乡村小道上去砸石头
they would have us out on some back road breaking rocks.
对  另一方面
Yeah, on the other hand...
《盗亦有道》里的保雷在监狱里接上电线
Paulie in Goodfellas had the joint wired,
每晚都煮丰盛的晚餐
cookin' big-ass dinners every night.
意大利人跟他们老妈的关系怪兮兮的
Italians have weird shit with their mothers.
他们跟老妈一起住的时间太长了
They, like, live with them for way too long.
我们跟老妈的关系都怪兮兮的
We all got weird shit with our mamas.
他们问起红妈的事  你会怎么说
What you gonna say when they ask you about Red?
说我啥也没看见  因为这是事实
That I didn't see shit, 'cause I didn't see shit.
可是你知道是谁干的
But, come on, you know who did it.
天呐  谁啊  谁干的
Oh, my gosh! Who? Who?
该死  你别一惊一乍的
Damn, you can't be doin' that shit.
我们家有心脏病史
I got a family history of heart attacks.
抱歉  对不起还不行吗
Sorry, I mean, I'm sorry. All right?
我就是过来看看家族生意怎么样
I just came to check on the family business.
毕竟我们得保证资金充足嘛
You know, we gotta keep these accounts full, right?
然后你们就开始闲聊了
And then you began to chat.
意大利人确实恋母
Italians do love their mamas.
那么
So...
你们有啥想问我的吗
Is there something you want to ask me?
-没  -没有
- Mmm-mmm. - Nope.
妈的  问不问我都要回答
Shit, I'm gonna answer anyway.
是我干的
Yes.
维  你知道我们啥也不会说的
Vee, you know we ain't gonna say shit.
你要说  亲爱的
Yes, you are, sweetheart.
你就说
You are going to say...
"你知道沃伦那丫头精神不稳定吗
"You know that Warren girl is unstable?
她有暴力史
She has a history of violence,
忠心不二
a melodramatic notion of loyalty.
但拜托对她下手别太狠
But please go easy on her because, you know what,
因为就算是疯子也需要点帮助"
even a double cray need a little bit of help."
他们大概最后就自己得出结论了
They will probably come to this conclusion on their own, eventually,
但帮他们一把也没啥坏处
but it doesn't hurt to give 'em a little push.
虽说她是精神病  但你这样也太冷血了吧
I know she Fruity Pebbles, but, man, that's cold.
是吗  真的
Is it? Really?
亚马逊调低书价
Is it cold for Amazon
就为了抢夺市场份额  这算冷血吗
to underprice books just to capture market-share?
我觉得你们作为这家公司的股东
No, it seems to me that as shareholders in this company,
已经对冷血免疫了
you are immune to the cold.
就像北极熊一样
Just like polar bears.
卖廉价书跟陷害疯子可不是一回事
Not sure cheap books is the same as pinning shit on Crazy.
你就不怕红妈醒来之后告诉他们真相吗
Ain't you worried Red's gonna wake up and tell them what happened?
不怕  像红妈这样的黑帮前辈不会那样做事
Nope, that is not how OGs like Red handle their business.
台词已经教给你了
You've got your script.
照着背就行
Follow it.
因为总有用不完的袜子  小丫头
'Cause there are always more socks, baby girl.
总有用不完的锁
Always more locks.
死对头
Enemies?
红妈和维以前有嫌隙
Well, Red and Vee, they had history.
你说的"维"是指伊冯・帕克吗
The Vee that you referenced is Yvonne Parker?
对  就是她
Yeah, yeah, that's her.
坏胚子
Bad seed.
靠近她的时候  你能感觉到她是个坏胚子
You can feel it when you're around her, her bad seediness.
就是她把局面搞得剑拔弩张
She is the one that made things hardcore.
虽说监狱不比夏令营
I mean, it's not like prison was summer camp,
但我们以前都能和平共处
but we all sort of got along.
起码不存在互相残杀
At least nobody was trying to kill each other.
结果现在分成了敌对的两派
Now, it's like Serbo-Croatia up in here.
你跟瑞泽尼科夫关系很近  对吧
You have a close relationship with Reznikov, correct?
别那么称呼她  她叫红妈
Don't call her that. Her name's Red, all right?
我们办理公务时不接受昵称
Nicknames don't suit our official purpose.
是吗  不把她当人对待
Oh, yeah. Yeah, well, treating her like she's not a person
我还不接受呢
doesn't suit me.
你们就做好本职工作
Hey, look, just do your job
找到那个混蛋凶手  好吗
and find the asshole who did it, okay?
如果你们够称职的话  现在就该查清楚了
All right, you'd know this by now if you were any good at your job.
是维干的
It was Vee.
她真名叫帕克  为了你们的公务需要
Parker, for your official purposes.
我觉得是那个黑人  扎小辫的那个
I think it's the black one. I don't know. The one with the hair.
她的真名不可能是"疯眼婆"
Her real name can't be Crazy Eyes.
我不知道  她就是个疯子
I don't know. She's the crazy one.
她之前就经常朝别人扔馅饼
She already be, like, throwing pie all the time...
但在这件事上  她的疯狂又更上了一层楼
but this is, like, next-level crazy, you know?
粗鲁
Rude.
那个维非常粗鲁
That Vee, she's a very rude person.
我不喜欢粗鲁的人
I don't like rude.
-是疯眼婆  -对
- It was Crazy Eyes. - Yes.
可你知道她的真名吗
But do you happen to know her real name?
苏珊娜・沃伦
Suzanne Warren.
你确定吗
You're sure?
确定
Positive.
我是从背后受到的攻击
I was attacked from behind.
我什么都没看见
I saw nothing.
没看到半个人影
No one.
我是个种种花草的老太婆
I'm an old woman trying to grow something green.
我真不知道谁会对我下此毒手
I don't know who would do this to me.
查普曼
Chapman.
卡普托先生
Mr. Caputo.
我喜欢你对这里所做的改变
I like what you've done with the place.
悲哀的是  这里已经开始有家的感觉了
Sadly, you know, it's starting to feel like home in here.
除了惩罚你  我别无选择
You know I had no choice but to punish you.
毕竟你闯进了行政办公室
You broke into administrative offices.
你说有人让你偷这些文件
You said someone asked you to steal these.
是谁
Who?
我还以为你不想听我说呢
I thought you weren't interested in what I had to say.
这里有一年的发票
There's a year's worth of invoices in here.
有人在搜集证据吗
Someone building a case?
我很清楚你想说些什么
'Cause I got a pretty good idea where you're going with this...
但我要知道些细节
but I'd like some details.
你...
You...
我刚来的时候  你对我很和善
you were kind to me when I got here.
你还让我给我未婚夫打了那个电话
You let me make that phone call to my fiance.
你这话的重点是什么
What's your point?
我的重点是  你是个好人
My point is that you're a good person.
而菲格罗亚女士
And Miss Figueroa...
她不是好人
she isn't.
她在挪用公款吗
Is she embezzling?
你像个用心工作的人
You seem like someone who cares about his job.
说实话
And frankly, you know,
我觉得如果这座监狱由你来管理的话会更好
I think this would be a better place if you were in charge.
你他妈给我说重点
Get to the fucking point.
你进了禁闭室  丫头
You're in seg, kid.
我很乐意让你一直留在这里
I'd be more than happy to leave you in here.
告诉我你到底在策划些什么
Now tell me exactly what you were planning.
我本想除掉她
I was gonna take her out.
"除掉她"
"Take her out."
怎么除
How?
那些文件
Those files...
是揭发她罪行的众多证据中的一小部分
are a small piece of a much bigger case against her.
我想知道你的外应是谁
I wanna know who your contact is on the outside.
你根本用不着他
You don't even need him.
我可以跟你解释那个文件夹里的所有内容
I can explain to you everything that is in that folder.
我保证会给你扳倒她所需的证据
I will give you all of the ammunition you need, I promise.
我全都告诉你
I will tell you everything.
有什么条件
If?
只要你别让我转狱
If you stop my transfer.
我抓住你了  你这个臭婊子
I got you now, you dirty bitch.
老天啊
Jesus.
你这是怎么了
What's going on in here?
你穿着运动裤就来上班了
You wearing sweatpants?
这是便裤啦
They're slacks.
好吧  你得深呼吸
All right. All right, you gotta... you gotta breathe.
深呼吸  对对对  快
Hey, take... take a deep breath. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Come on now.
杰森
Jason...
乔  我是乔
Joe. I'm... I'm Joe.
不  我丈夫是杰森
No, my husband is Jason.
他怎么了  被捕了吗
Huh. What happened to him? He get arrested?
不是
No!
他出轨了
He's having an affair with a...
对象是个叫加文的男人
man named... Gavin.
加文
Gavin?
老天  这事闹的
Jeez. Yikes.
他坠入爱河了
He's in love.
这...
That's, uh...
我怎么就没看出来呢  我脑子进水了吗
How did I not know? What's wrong with me?
你完全不知道吗
You had no idea?
有很多男人都会剃蛋蛋上的毛
A lot of men shave their balls.
这又不能说明他们就是同性恋
It doesn't mean they're gay.
要知道这不是因为你不够好
You know it's not you, right?
你得知道这一点
Hey, you gotta know that, huh?
有些东西是娘胎里带来的
People are born a certain way, you know...
他曾经是爱我的
He used to love me.
我相信
I'm sure he did.
老天啊  瞧我现在的样子
Oh, Christ, look at me.
我以前那么惹火
I used to be so... hot.
现在我皮肤粗硬  满脸褶子
Now I'm... hard and... wrinkled.
你还是很惹火  菲格
You're still hot, Fig.
虽说你是个烂人  但还是性感得要命
I mean, you're a horrible person... but you're sexy as hell.
真的吗
Really?
真的
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
见鬼  你为他挪用了那么多公款  结果...
Hell, after all that money you embezzled for him...
什么  你这是什么意思
Wait, what? What are you talking about?
挪用公款  诈骗
Embezzlement. Fraud.
我拿到你的文件了
I've got your files.
你一直都不乖哦
You've been a bad girl.
我要是你老爸  肯定会狠狠打你屁股
And if I was your daddy, I'd spank you real good...
可我不是
but I'm not.
我只不过是个一直为你擦屁股的笨蛋
I'm just the schmuck who's been cleaning up your crap for too long
现在我受够了
and I'm done.
你是个该死的罪犯  "肥"格罗亚夫人
You're a goddamn criminal, Mrs. Fagueroa.
滚出去
Get out.
好吧
Fine.
不  站住  你不能走
No, wait, stop. You can't.
不能吗
I can't?
舔我的老二吧  娜塔莉
Suck my dick, Natalie.
好啊
Okay.
等等  你说什么
Wait, what?
不是吧
Holy shit.
Holy shit!
是啊  高中同学都叫我"金箍棒"
Yeah, they used to call me beer can in high school.
咬到我了  疼
Ah, teeth, teeth.
对不起
Sorry.
这事一笔勾销了吧
So we're good?
我确实喜欢你对我卑躬屈膝
I do like you down on your knees.
老天  你就该永远别开口说话
Christ, you should... never speak.
那些文件你不会上报了吧
The files. You'll shut up?
我已经交给典狱长了
Oh, I... I already gave 'em to the warden.
他手上有所有的副本
He's got copies of everything.
再见  娜
Bye, Nat.
操
Fuck!
你为什么啥都没跟特别调查处说
Why didn't you say anything to SIS?
你为什么要保护那个娘们
Why would you protect that woman?
那个娘们有办法躲过一切麻烦
That woman can weasel her way out of anything.
我要用自己的方式处理这件事
I'm handling this my way.
她敲碎了你的眼窝
She cracked your eye socket.
会痊愈的
Hmm, it will heal.
这给了我时间来平静地策划报复方案
And this gives me time to plan in peace.
你根本都坐不起来  还谈什么策划
Kind of hard to plan when you can't even sit up.
我以前会带儿子们去科尼岛
I used to take the boys to Coney Island.
他们可喜欢旋转飞车了
They loved the spinning rides.
他们称其为"醉醉飞车"
They called them the "Mamochka drunk rides"
因为我下来之后总是会恶心  走路不稳
because I'd always get off nauseous and stumbling.
那群小混蛋觉得很搞笑
Little shits thought it was hilarious.
我现在就是那种感觉
This is the same feeling...
只不过少了三个小男孩对我指指点点地嘲笑
but without three little boys pointing and laughing at me.
你应该让管理部门处理这件事
You should let the administration handle this.
管理部门用管子给你强制喂食
I should trust the administration...
就这样你还让我信任他们啊
while they're force-feeding you through tubes.
说得很有道理
Salient point.
拜托你告诉我菲格的办公桌里有根自慰棒
Look, please tell me that Fig keeps a vibrator in her desk.
我脑海里有一幅关于她的清晰画面
'Cause I have this crystal-clear image in my head of her there,
双脚抬起来  高跟鞋踢翻了笔筒
feet up, high heels knocking over the pen cup
拿着自慰棒  按摩阴蒂  爽翻了天
while she just goes to town on her clit with a pocket rocket.
她的抽屉里全是零食和包装纸
Her drawers are full of snacks and wrappers.
不是吧  简直幻灭啊
Oh, come on. Man, don't tell me that.
我不想把她想象成满嘴呕吐味的贪食症患者
I don't wanna think of her as a bulimic with barf breath.
这也太没劲了
It's just so...
不过有个好消息  卡普托取消了我的转狱
Good news though. Caputo canceled my transfer.
太棒了  你可以继续待在地狱了
Whoopie. You get to stay here... in hell.
你可能会被精神失常的毒贩子
Hey, maybe you'll get slocked to death
活活打死呢
by a psychotic heroin dealer.
红妈怎么样了
How's Red?
还活着  我就知道这么多
Alive. It's all I know.
这他妈就是个奇迹
And that's a fucking miracle, you know.
医疗区那边没传出什么消息
Not a ton of news coming out of the medical unit, so...
抱歉  妮琪
I'm sorry, Nicky.
即便所有人都知道这事是谁干的
No, I mean, those ass clowns launched their bullshit investigation
那群跳梁小丑仍然要做该死的调查
even though everyone knows exactly who did it, but...
你或许该把转狱的机会争取回来
You know, maybe you should ask for your transfer back.
离开这个鬼地方
Just get the fuck out of here.
待在这里总比转狱强
It's better than the alternative.
我不能再失去任何人了  妮琪
I can't lose any more people, Nicky.
艾丽克斯要来看我了
Alex is coming to visit me.
天啊  查普曼
Jesus, Chapman.
你得搞清楚你他妈想要什么
You need to figure out what the fuck you want.
我知道
I know.
如果你真的想待在这个鬼地方
You know, 'cause if it really is to stay here in this shithole
好让你那个神经病女朋友偶尔来看看你
so you can get occasional visits from your demented girlfriend,
那你算是梦想照进现实了
I mean, then, man, it sounds like you're living the dream.
但我的建议是
But if you want my advice,
你就别在这瞎矫情了
then get out of your own goddamn drama for a minute, you know?
还是多花点精力祈祷
And, maybe, spend some of that energy praying
你室友能健健康康地
that your roommate makes it out of medical
从医疗区出来
with all her brain cells intact.
抱歉  妮琪  我没想一直扯自己的事
I'm sorry, Nicky. I didn't mean to make this about me.
没关系  我懂  你对这事没那么上心
No, don't worry. I get it. It's not the same for you.
我也很关心红妈
I care about Red, too.
但她不是你妈  这事对我们家人来说不一样
Okay, but she's not your mom. It's different when you're family.
姐妹  别哭了
Mama, please.
这道破菜不加你的眼泪就已经够咸了
This shit is salty enough without your tears in it.
你想休息一会吗
You wanna take a break? Ven.
今天有什么好菜  本尼特  我饿了
What's looking good today, Bennett? I'm a hungry man.
今天有烤鸡  不过看着有点糊
There's some baked chicken but it looks a little gray.
我打算继续吃花生酱果冻三明治
I tend to stick with the PB and J.
那边怎么了
What's going on over there?
卢茨在菲格拟定的转狱名单上
Oh, well, you know, Ruiz is on the transfer list that Fig put out.
很让人难过  她还有孩子什么的
It's really sad. She's got the baby and everything. It's...
我要取消所有转狱
I'm canceling all the transfers.
真的吗  怎么做到的
Really? How?
你能保密吗
Can you keep a secret?
当然能
Yeah, absolutely.
你看样子也能
Yeah, you seem like it.
听着
Okay, listen.
发生了一些变故
Some stuff has gone down,
我的星星可能会冉冉升起
and it looks like my star might be rising
而菲格的星星要爆炸了
while Fig's explodes.
你懂我的意思吗
You know what I'm saying?
不太懂
Not really.
她出局了
She's out.
我当权了
I'm in.
差不多可以这么说
Well, in-ish.
我得向典狱长证明我是他的合适人选
I gotta show the warden I'm his guy.
他在考察我
He's testing me out.
这事一定得进展顺利  本尼特
Yeah, this has gotta go well, Bennett.
接下来几天很关键
The next few days are crucial.
我们得确保顺利
We gotta make sure.
我想有好的表现
I wanna do things right.
随着我一起提携你这样的人
Bring guys like you up along with me.
好人
The good guys.
时刻警惕  安分守己的人
The guys who keep their eyes open and their noses clean.
这听起来不错  先生
Sounds... that sounds great, sir.
听着
So, listen...
你何不去把这个好消息告诉卢茨呢
why don't you go give Ruiz the good news?
说她不会转狱了
Tell her she's not going anywhere.
-我  -对
- Me? - Yeah.
做她的英雄  去吧
Be the hero. Go ahead.
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you. Um, thanks a lot.
去吧  去吧  孩子
Go ahead, go ahead. Go ahead, kid.
出什么事了
What's going on?
我要取消卢茨的转狱
I'm canceling Ruiz's transfer.
她可以留下了
She's staying put.
你人真好
So nice of you.
我尽力而为
I do what I can.
天啊
Oh, my God!
你能端这么重的盘子吗
Hey, should you be carrying such a heavy tray?
没关系  谢谢
That's fine, thanks.
这样更好
It's better!
-听着  美味  -住嘴
- Listen, T... - Stop.
我们能不能别讨论
Can we please not have a whole talk about
我们的感觉  发生的事情和现在的状态
our feelings and what happened and, like, status
因为我不会来这一套
because I never learned that and...
这让我浑身不自在
and it really makes me, like, wanna jump out of my skin so...
我们能不能就这么坐着  平静相处
can we just sit here and be cool now?
就聊一小会行吗
Well, maybe just a little talk?
如果阿曼达要聊起这事呢
I mean... Look, what if Amanda talked about it... right?
比如她跟马姆西的操蛋关系
Like, her fucked-up relationship with Mumsy
他们去西班牙寻欢作乐的时候
and how hard that made things with Mackenzie
麦肯锡心里有多不好受
when they took that cruise to Spain and shit.
你能像那样聊聊吗
Could you do it like that?
我试试吧
I'll work on it, okay?
我发誓
I swear.
我跟我的古鲁约了见面
I have an appointment to meet with my guru
马上就能拿到一段祷文
to get a mantra soon
在那之后我就开始跟你聊
so I'll start right after that.
但要赶在我嘴唇注射屁股脂肪之前
But before I get my lips injected with ass fat
不然嘴太肿了没法聊
so that we can really talk.
"屁股脂肪"
"Ass fat."
给  你看起来像只猴子
Here... because you look like a monkey.
该死  我没有花生可以给你
Oh, damn, here I am with no peanuts for you.
-我就吃你的果冻补充点明胶  -不行
- I'll just take your Jell-O for gelatin! - No!
死也不给你  妈的
Like hell you will! Shit.
你知道我最爱吃红色口味的
You know red my favorite flavor!
是啊
Yeah.
你是个禽兽
You're an animal.
你那个袜子包密码锁的小把戏
And your little electroslock therapy?
骗不了大家伙
You're not fooling anyone.
请告诉我的老朋友红妈
Please tell my old friend, Red, that I...
我希望她感觉好些了
I hope she feels better.
你真是个混账朋友
Some flipping friend you are.
你们这些人有什么毛病
What's the matter with you people?
"你们这些人"  你是指黑人吗
"You people"? You mean black people?
我是指盲人
I mean, blind people. All right?
盲目地跟从一个该死的精神病
Blindly following a fucking psychopath!
好了  小朋友们
All right, little ones.
如果你们对我指责谩骂完了
Now, if you're done with your accusations and your name-calling,
就让我们安宁地吃完这顿饭吧
we'd all like to finish our meal in peace.
愿你永远不得安宁
May you never have a minute of peace.
有你们俩在我旁边  我肯定安宁不了
I trust with you two around, I won't.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我们会缠着你的
We'll be around.
闭上你的臭嘴
Shut the fuck up.
你们俩又重归于好了  真要命
Aw, you bitches friends again? Oh, now...
整得跟《牛仔裤的夏天》里的闺蜜似的
ain't that some Sisterhood of the Traveling Pants shit?
你们都知道是她干的
I mean, ya'll know she done it.
你觉得她以后不会对你下手吗
You don't think she won't go after your ass one day?
万一惹毛了她  瞅她的眼神不对啥的
You make her mad... look at her wrong... whatever?
现在局势不错  我不会找麻烦的
Look, business is good, and I ain't rocking the boat.
我们就不能和平相处吗
Can't we all just get along?
不行
No...
起码有她在的时候不行
not when she's around.
你们现在还看不清状况  也别怪自己
Don't feel bad if you don't see it yet.
我花了15年才搞明白
Took me damn near 15 years.
我只希望你们趁为时太晚之前放聪明点
I just hope you all wise up before it's too late.
你自己来决定
It's up to you.
你可以整个小甜甜崩溃时期的光头
You could go full-on Britney Spears meltdown.
不行  万万不能剃"化疗头"
Oh, no. Cancer chic is anything but.
不过我觉得艾玛・沃特森那种小仙子的短发会很萌
Now, I'm thinking a nice Emma Watson pixie'll be cute, though.
谢谢你们的建议
I appreciate your guys' choices,
不过我想剪到这里
but I'm thinking, like, right here.
你是说像贝嫂那样吗
Oh, you mean like Victoria Beckham?
抱歉  小宝贝  盖过耳朵就不算短发
Sorry, shortcake, above the ears or it doesn't count.
想跟哥哥们混
Hey, you wanna run with the big boys,
你就得证明自己是我们中的一员
you gotta prove you're one of us, hmm?
我还以为这是个女性组织
I thought this was about the girls.
挺迷惑人的  我知道
It's confusing, I know.
我要取消安全地带
I'm canceling Safe Place.
我就是来通知你一声
I thought you should know.
为什么
Why?
等等
Wait!
海利先生  等等
Mr. Healy, wait!
你男朋友伤心了吗
Aw, is your boyfriend hurt?
别说这种话
Don't do that.
进来
Come in!
老大
Hey, boss.
你好  奥尼尔  今天你过得怎样
Hello, O'Neill. How are you on this fine day?
我很好  谢谢
Oh, I'm good, thanks.
我网购了一把班卓里里琴
I bought a banjolele on Craigslist.
我不知道那是什么东西
I don't know what that is.
就是四弦班卓琴  不过很小
It's like a four-stringed banjo, but little.
就是尤克里里版的班卓琴
It's... you know, it's a ukulele version of a banjo.
这个问题算是搞明白了
Asked and answered.
除了你可爱的网购消息之外
So, aside from the news of your adorable online purchase,
你来找我还有其他事情吗
is there another reason for your visit?
对了
Oh, yeah, um...
你想怎么处理那群修女
What do you wanna do about the nuns?
-修女  -对啊  门口聚了一票
- Nuns? - Yeah, there's a gaggle of 'em.
一票
Gaggle?
就像是"一群"乌鸦  门口有"一票"修女
Uh, like a... like a murder of crows, there's a gaggle of nuns.
我们来支持简・英格尔斯的绝食抗议
We're here to support Jane Ingalls' hunger strike.
上帝啊
Oh, Jesus.
说话小心点
Watch your mouth.
我今天惹不起这种麻烦
I can't have this today.
现在不行  你们来的太不是时候了
Not now. I... Your timing could not have been worse.
抱歉给你们带来不便
So sorry to inconvenience you.
修女  我是好人
Look, Sister... I'm the good guy.
我想办好事
I... I want things to be good.
你们能过三至五天再来吗
Could you come back in three to five days?
不行
No, I could not.
我必须得问一句
I had to ask.
看好这群修女
Babysit the nuns.
先生  我觉得这样不太妥  我跟修女有过节
Sir, I don't think that's a good idea. I got a history with nuns.
给我忍着
Suck it up.
让她们老老实实的  别闹事
I need things calm and contained. No drama.
如果媒体来了  就打电话给我
And if the press comes, you call me.
但不是我干的
But it wasn't me.
很好
That's very good.
你去跟特别调查处谈话的时候就这么说
That is exactly what you say when you go in there to talk to SIS.
这样好极了  苏珊娜
It's perfect, Suzanne.
不  维  真的不是我
No, Vee... it really wasn't me.
不是我干的
I didn't do it!
闺女  你认准一件事还就真不改口了
Child, when you commit, you really do commit, don't you?
我欣赏你这点
I admire that.
私下里  我想谢谢你  小丫头
Between us... I just wanna say thank you, little girl.
虽说你的手段很凶残  但这事总要有人干
What you did was rough... but it had to be done.
维
Vee...
我们不该再聊咱俩的事了
We shouldn't talk about us anymore.
我从小卖部给你买了一样特别的东西
I got you something special from the commissary.
我们以后可以玩
We can play later.
咱们俩
You and me.
她是这么说的
All right, it's like this.
住嘴  别跟我说话
Stop... don't talk to me.
废柴  蠢小子  跟风货
Loser, lame-boy, wannabe. Oh!
你绝对就是想成为我  保持新鲜
Like, totally, all you wanna be is me. Stay fresh.
好了  你来学一遍
Okay, now you try.
她是这么说的
Okay, so it's like...
住嘴  别跟我说话  废柴  蠢蛋  跟风货
Stop, don't talk to me. Loser, lame-ass, wannabe.
小子  是"蠢小子"
Boy. It's "Lame-boy."
可我们学的是佩萨塔琪
Yeah, but we're talkin' Pennsatucky.
她不该说"蠢蛋"或"蠢丫头"什么的吗
So shouldn't it be, like, "lame-ass" or "lame-girl"?
你们真是可悲的混蛋
Y'all are sad fucking assholes.
这就是欺负人
You know, this is really bullying.
虽说你们有权利对佩萨塔琪有消极情绪
While you have every right to your negative feelings towards Pennsatucky,
但这样太残忍了  我觉得你们俩没那么差劲
you're being cruel... and I think you're both better than that.
拥抱光明吧
Embrace the light.
我能照顾好自己  中国重庆妞
You know, I can take care of myself, Ching Chong China doll!
她是日本苏格兰混血  你这个无知的笨蛋
She's Japanese-Scottish, you ignorant dumb-ass.
无知的笨蛋女同
Ignorant dumb-ass dyke.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我们都看见你跟那个胖胖的假小子混了
Like we haven't seen you hanging out with fatty-fatty man-girl.
是吗  那又怎样
Oh, yeah? So what?
你们这么骂人是闹哪样啊
What is with all this name calling?
我们在表达自己的情绪
We're expressing our feelings...
以此代替身体暴力
in lieu of physical violence.
这是海利先生教我的
Something Mr. Healy taught me.
-是吗  -是的
- Oh, yeah? - Yep.
那你之前跑哪去了
Then where were you before?
没人去参加他的安全地带
No one came to his Safe Place thing, you know.
他既伤心又生气
He was all sad and mad.
我拿走了他奇怪的俄罗斯饼干  击个掌
And I got his weird Russian cookies. Up top!
这里的所有人都既伤心又生气
Everyone in this place is sad and mad.
我懂  我们在坐牢  这很操蛋
I mean, I get it. We're in prison. It sucks.
但我们应该彼此依靠
But we should be leaning on each other...
在狱友之间寻找支持
finding support in our fellow criminals...
这样我们就不会孤立了
so we're not isolated.
我需要个朋友
I need a friend.
别看我
Don't look at me.
我已经有朋友了
I got a friend.
没人去参加安全地带吗
Nobody showed up at Safe Place?
对  一个人都没有
Nope, not a one.
以后都没有安全地带了  这大概都是你的错
And no more Safe Place. It's probably all your fault.
这简直太奇怪了
Okay, this is totally weird.
我穿的衣服不对
I'm in the wrong outfit.
我喜欢你的毛衣
I like your sweater.
很柔软
It's soft.
就像你拿到认罪条件时软塌塌的决心
Like your resolve when you're offered a plea deal.
我是最后一刻才决定的  帕波
It came down at the very last minute, Piper.
而且他们向我保证会关他一辈子
And they promised me it would put him away for good.
但这让我变成了伪证者  而你获得了自由身
But it made me a perjurer and you a free woman.
我还以为你会说实话呢
I thought you were gonna tell the truth!
我还以为你会撒谎呢
And I thought you were gonna lie!
老天啊  咱俩简直就像一篇欧亨利小说
Jesus, we are like a fucking O. Henry story.
能看到你的脸真好
It's good to see your face.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
你完全有权利生气
You have every right to be angry.
我都不知道自己生不生气
I don't know if I'm angry.
我被你搞糊涂了
I'm confused... by you.
我也被自己搞糊涂了
I'm confused by me, too.
我最擅长的就是收拾烂摊子
I'm pretty much the master of handling things completely wrong.
你说得真够婉转的
Yeah, well, that's an understatement.
我一团糟
I'm a fuck-up.
而我现在住在皇后区的破公寓里
And now I get to be a fuck-up in a shithole apartment in Queens.
害怕得连窗帘都不敢拉开
Too afraid to even open my curtains.
我快要孤独死了  帕波
I'm really fucking lonely, Piper.
你一定会找到帮你暖床的人
Well, I'm sure you'll find somebody to keep your bed warm.
我搂着枪一起睡
I sleep with a gun.
什么  艾丽克斯  搞什么鬼  你在服缓刑啊
You what? Alex, what the hell? You're on probation.
我公寓外面每天都停着一辆车
There is a car parked outside of my apartment every day.
他是想吓我
He's trying to scare me.
我想拎着一根棒球棒出去
I wanna go out there with a baseball bat
把那该死的挡风玻璃砸了
and smash the fucking windshield in.
说实话  我应该重新开始贩毒
Honestly, I should just start dealing again.
找个能盖过我以前那个老板的更大更猛的毒枭
Find a bigger, tougher new kingpin who can beat up my old kingpin.
-这可不好笑  -这不是个笑话
- That's not funny. - It's not a joke.
我有资格做什么呢
What am I qualified to do?
我没有工作  害怕离开自己的公寓
I have... I have no job. I'm afraid to leave my apartment.
因为我太怕黑
I got so used to sleeping with the lights on
现在已经习惯了开灯睡
that I'm totally freaked out by the dark.
我的缓刑官是个笑话  他叫大卫・克罗克特
My probation officer is a joke. His name is David Crockett.
大卫・克罗克特是我的缓刑官
Davy fucking Crockett is my probation officer.
跟电影《大卫克罗传》重名吗
The King of the Wild Frontier?
这个肥臀佬整天就知道坐着
King of sitting on his fat fucking ass,
往嘴里塞蛋糕卷
stuffing his face with Swiss rolls,
巴不得逮到我做出犯傻的违规行为
hoping to bust me for some stupid infraction.
保护缓刑犯
You'd think that part of his job
原本该是他的职责之一
would be protecting his probies, you know?
没人在乎前科犯
Nobody gives a shit about ex-cons.
你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
-我要逃走  -不行
- I'm skipping town. - You can't.
我别无选择  这些人知道我住在哪
I don't have a choice. These people know where I live.
所以我才想见你
That's why I wanted to see you.
帕波  我走了之后  就没法回头了
When I go, Piper, I can't come back.
我得销声匿迹
I have to just disappear.
你不能离开我
You can't leave me.
帕波  我身处危险之中
Piper, I'm in danger.
但我只剩你一个人了
But I don't have anyone left.
对不起  帕波
I'm sorry, Piper.
我为所有的一切向你道歉
I'm sorry for all of it.
虽说我劣迹斑斑
I know that my track record is shit...
但我真心爱你
but I really do love you.
好吧  我恨你
Yeah, well, I hate you.
不  你不恨我
No, you don't.
对
No.
我不恨你
No, I don't.
你好  瘾君子
Hey, junkie.
你好  混蛋叛徒
Hey, you traitorous piece of shit.
该洗涤一下你那肮脏的灵魂了
It's time to start scrubbing that dirty little soul of yours.
这我倒不担心
Well, I wouldn't worry about it too much.
我在用玉米糖浆慢性自杀
I'm slowly killing myself with corn syrup.
大波  你出卖了她
Boo, you sold her out.
她躺在医院里也有你的一份责任
You're part of why she's lying in that hospital bed.
听着
All right, look.
你得弥补才行
You need to make it right.
你想让我怎么做
What do you want me to do about it?
用我的左屁股蛋子把帕克闷死在睡梦中吗
Smother Parker in her sleep with my left ass cheek?
我爱人  不打人
I'm a lover, not a fighter.
得了吧
Aw, come on.
你最知道伤害某人的方法有千万种
You, of all people, know there's a million ways to hurt someone.
所以告诉我这个老朋友  她把她的东西藏在哪了
So tell your old pal, Nicky, where she stashes her shit.
挖出你最后一丝未泯的忠诚吧
Find that last shred of loyalty.
你在哪
Where are you?
你在哪啊
这是怎么回事
What... What's going on, yo?
我找不到它了  我知道原本就在这里
I can't find it! I know it was here.
现在不在了  我知道原本就在这里
Now it's not here. I know it was here!
22左  14右  9左  我知道原本就在这里
Twenty-two left, 14 right, 9 left. I know it was here!
-你的锁吗  -嘘
- Your lock? - Shh!
锁美人
Lady Locksley.
妈的  我觉得她可能做坏事了
Oh, shit. I think she might've done something bad.
你这是什么意思
What are you talking about?
我觉得是我干的
I think I did it.
我觉得自己袭击了那个俄罗斯老太
I think I attacked that Russian lady,
一下又一下地打了她
and hit and hit and hit her!
你"觉得"
Yo, you think?
苏珊娜  如果是你干的  难道你不该"知道"吗
Suzanne, if you done it, don't you think you would know?
不  我不总知道自己在干什么
No, I don't always know what I'm doing.
有时候我会屏蔽一些事情  某些坏事
You know, sometimes I block stuff out, some bad stuff like...
比如我那次对我邻居做的那件事
like that time I did the thing to my neighbor.
听起来你并没把那件事屏蔽掉
It don't sound like you blocked that out.
确实没有
Well... no.
那件事还历历在目  但维说是我干的
That one's still pretty vivid. But Vee says I did it.
苏珊娜  维是个骗子
Yo, Suzanne... Vee is a liar.
不是
No. No, no, no.
No, no, no.
她说的是实话  这是她告诉我的
She is a truth teller. She told me that.
她说  我们说真的
She says... we're straight up.
建立在诚实和忠诚的基础上
Built on a foundation of honesty and loyalty.
我看是建立在屁话的基础上
Yo, built on a foundation of bullshit, more like.
你觉得那个女人对你忠诚吗
You think that woman loyal to you?
她在耍你  这场游戏是玩真的
She is playing you, and this game is for serious.
如果你这次顶了罪  就要去重刑监狱
You take the blame on this, you going to max.
你会被判谋杀未遂
You getting rapped with attempted murder.
你什么都没干  为什么要顶罪呢
Yo, why would you take the blame when you ain't done nothing?
那个女人是恶魔
That woman is evil
她想陷害你  伤害你
and she's trying to frame you and do you harm...
你不准说她坏话
No, don't you dare speak ill of her!
她告诉过我你会说坏话
You know, she told me you'd say bad things.
她警告过我  现在被她说中了
Yeah, she warned me, and now here you are doing just that.
-苏珊娜  -所以
- Suzanne. - So...
我觉得你最好走吧
I think you'd better go.
你这个可怜疯狂的大傻瓜
You poor, crazy fool.
不
No.
我没疯
I am not crazy.
我这叫独特
I am unique.
以前有部电视剧
There used to be this show on TV
讲的是不知道自己怀了孕的女孩们
about girls who, like, had no idea they were pregnant.
我总是想"是有可能啊
And I always thought, "Yeah, I could see that.
你们有点发胖  觉得自己不再性感了"
You're kind of chunky. You don't feel so hot, anyway."
但我现在觉得这纯属瞎扯
But now I'm calling bullshit on it.
我也没太显怀
I mean, I'm... I'm not all that popping out or anything.
阿蕾达说我们家的女人把孩子怀在屁股里
Aleida says the women in our family carry in our ass,
但我能感觉到她
but... I feel her.
我真的能感觉到她
I really feel her in there.
达娅  我...
Daya, I, uh...
我不能告诉别人
I can't tell anyone.
不  听我说
No, look. Listen to me.
菲格出事了
Something happened with Fig.
挪用公款还是什么的
Embezzling or something.
卡普托要升职了
Caputo's getting promoted.
他说我也会拿到升职
He says that I'm looking at a promotion, too.
现在承认这件事太不理智了
It'll be crazy to come clean right now.
这意味着我们能赚更多钱
This means more money for us.
这意味着你当不成孩子的父亲
This means you can't be the dad.
别这样  宝贝  我们会想出办法的
Come on, baby. Look, hey, we'll figure it out.
别把菲格的事说出去  好吗
Don't say anything about the Fig thing, okay?
现在还是个秘密
It's still on the down-low.
你之前在找借口
Well, you were looking for an excuse.
而这次升职加薪是最好的借口
I guess this raise/promotion thing is as good as any.
我这不是在找借口
I'm not looking for an excuse.
我爱你  约翰
I love you, John...
但你是个缩头乌龟
but you're a pussy.
我得回去工作了
I gotta get back to work.
达娅
Daya...
达娅  我是支潜力股
Daya, I'm a man on the rise.
我不是...
I'm not a...
说真的  别把菲格的事说出去  好吗
Seriously, don't say anything about the Fig thing, okay?
这是个秘密
It was told to me in confidence.
拜托了
Please?
这么说菲格出局了
So Fig's out?
我就知道那个皮包骨头的婊子在捣鬼
I knew that skinny puta was pulling some shit.
她从来笑不露齿
She never smile with her teeth.
不能相信一个笑不露齿的婊子
Can't trust a bitch don't smile with her teeth.
不过她有不少漂亮的鞋子
She has some nice shoes though, man.
你看到那娘们穿的鞋了吗
Yo, you seen the footwear on that one?
如果她在捞钱  肯定都用来买鞋了
If she was stealing, you know exactly where that money was going.
如果我捞了一笔大钱
If I was stealing big,
我会买一样穿着不会被磨坏的东西
I would buy me something that won't wear out from walking around.
比如在肚脐眼里镶颗钻石  说真的
Like a diamond for my belly button. No, for real.
很不错吧
That's nice. Yeah, right?
这就够了  看起来很不错
That's enough. It looks good.
快瞧瞧诺尔玛・苹果核啊
Well... would you look at Norma Appleseed over here.
你在种什么  果园吗
What are you planting, an orchard?
不  我知道你在打什么主意
No, I know what you're up to.
你想用什么来磨这些苹果核
What were you gonna use to grind them?
瞧你啊  不动声色地下毒手
Look at you... quiet fire.
你知道需要多少种子
Well, you know how many seeds you're gonna need
才够制出一剂致命的砒霜吗
to make a lethal dose of arsenic?
比你认识的所有老师
More than all the apples ever given
收到过的所有苹果还要多
to any teacher you've ever known.
然后你还需要搅拌机和碱液
And then you're gonna need a blender, you're gonna need lye,
还需要一只密封容器
and you're gonna need an airtight container.
然后你还要让维吃下去
And then you gotta get it down Vee's fucking throat.
姐妹  这件事你想得不够周全啊
Ay, Mama, you didn't think this one through.
我大概知道几件事
Yeah... I know a few things.
我知道她伤害了你的姑娘
I know she hurt your girl.
我知道她该死  但是
And I know she gotta go, but...
还有其他办法
there are other ways.
你只要对我开口就行
All you gotta do is ask.
今晚  我希望你们回家查一下
Okay, tonight, I want you to go home and look up
"小美洲豹杀死狒狒  并试图收养其孩子"
"Leopard cub kills baboon and tries to adopt its baby."
然后明天再回来
Then you come back tomorrow
告诉我孩子生来是有罪的
and you tell me babies are born with sin.
你给我们概述一下呗
Why don't you give us the highlights?
好吧
Okay, fine.
一只小美洲豹杀了一只狒狒
A leopard cub kills a baboon, right?
然后正当美洲豹准备
And then as the leopard's
把狒狒的尸体拖回家当晚餐的时候
dragging the bloody baboon corpse home for dinner,
一只小狒狒从它死去妈妈的怀抱里掉了出来
a baby baboon falls from the folds of its dead mother.
你在想"美洲豹会吃掉小狒狒"对吧
And you're thinking, "Leopard's gonna eat the baby," Right?
在主菜之前先吃只小狒狒开个胃
A little baby baboon appetizer before the main course?
但是它保护了那只小狒狒
But, no, he shelters the baby.
它甚至帮小狒狒挡走了一只鬣狗
He even defends it against a hyena.
为什么
And why?
为什么这只野兽要那么做
Why would this wild animal do that?
因为即便是一只凶猛野蛮的食肉野兽
Because even a feral, wild, predatory beast...
也能察觉到天真无邪
can recognize innocence when it sees it
感觉自己需要去保护它
and feels the need to protect it.
但天主教徒却不能
Yet Catholics can't.
你有什么毛病啊
Hey, what is your problem?
我有什么毛病
What's my problem?
我看不惯天主教学校
Catholic school... that's my problem.
你们这群人整天上帝不离口
You people seem all "La, la, la, God,"
但在现实当中  你们可会羞辱人了
but in reality, you are professional humiliators!
某人在学校被尺子打了吗
Oh, did someone get rapped with a ruler?
忘了吧  你是个成年人了
Get over it. You're a grown up.
别纠结了
Let it go.
可那只小狒狒最后怎么样了
But what happened to the baby baboon?
它因暴露于户外而死
It died of exposure.
这大概是上帝的旨意
I suppose it was God's will.
胡说八道
Nonsense.
只是天气太冷了
It was just really cold.
就像修女的内心一样
Like a nun's heart.
操
Oh, fuck.
修女也会说"操"啊
Nuns say, "Fuck"?
我现在不是修女了
I'm a former nun.
她们都来了
They all came.
谁知道我还这么有号召力呢
Who knew I still had juice?
你难道不高兴吗  你的朋友为你而来
Aren't you pleased? Your friends showed up for you.
我得思考些其他事情
I need to think about something else.
我一直对饼干产生幻想
I keep... having fantasies about biscuits.
你铺好了床
You made your bed.
你现在可以躺在床上  开始输液了
Now you can lie in it, strapped to an IV.
是有两只输液袋吗  我眼前重影了
Or is it two IVs? I'm seeing double.
看起来像是床上有两个你
Looks like there's two of you in that bed.
我倒想呢
I wish.
是吗
You do?
我一直好奇
I always wondered about
你们修女的禁欲问题
that whole celibacy thing with you people.
到底是怎么一回事
How does that work?
如果你读报纸的话
Well, if you read the papers,
就会知道每个人禁欲的程度不同
you know better in some cases than in others.
那你呢
What about with you?
你有过...
Did you ever...
我自慰过
I've masturbated.
有一尊耶稣被钉十字架的雕像
There's this statue of Jesus on the cross
肌肉线条很清晰
that was especially ripped.
他就是我的意淫对象
He was my guy.
在德米特里之前  我有个男友叫帕维尔
Before Dmitri, there was this man named Pavel.
即便现在提起他  我都木耳一紧
Even talking about him now... there's a tightening.
后来发生了什么
So what happened?
美国  自由之乡
America... home of the free.
德米特里在床上温驯  生活中却敢闯
Dmitri was tame in bed, bold in life.
而帕维尔刚好相反
Pavel, the opposite.
我选择了生活
I went with life.
我选择了要去美国的那个男人
I went with the man who was going to go to America.
那不喜欢跟你丈夫做爱吗
So, you didn't like having sex with your husband?
倒不能这么说
I wouldn't say that, no.
我喜欢性爱
I like sex.
我从来都不会做完之后想
I never rolled away after and thought,
"真希望没做"
"Oh, I wish I hadn't done that."
性爱总是美好的
No, it was always nice.
但我有一种情结
But there's a part of me...
其实每个女人都有一种不想要"美好"的情结
a part of every woman, I think, that doesn't want nice.
这是婚后性爱的通病
That's the problem with married sex in general.
不再有恐惧
No more fear.
恐惧是好事吗
Fear is good?
恐惧好极了
Fear is very good.
但我要替我背上毛发浓密的丈夫说句话
But I'll say this for my hairy-backed husband...
他一直都很照顾我
he always took care of me.
撩拨他的欲望
Turned him on.
光是口活就能做半天
Could spend weeks down there.
我很享受这种释放
I do enjoy the release.
让我一身轻松
It cracks my neck.
不用了  谢谢你
No, thank you.
得了吧  别搞绝食这一套了
Oh, come on. Stop it with this nonsense.
相信我  我超想吃那个三明治
Believe me, all I want is to eat that sandwich,
但有一百个修女在外助阵  我不能放弃抗议啊
but I can't break my strike with 100 nuns out there.
请端走吧
Please take it away!
你竟然还担心你的朋友怎么看待你
You still worry about what your friends think?
你觉得我这是小孩子气吗
You think I'm acting childish?
是谁像小混混一样在床上策划复仇行动来着
Who's the one plotting revenge in her bed like a gangbanger?
给
Here.
吃点三明治面包  我们就能高潮  安宁地服刑
We can sandwich toast to orgasms and do our time in peace.
你要跟特别调查处的人揭发帕克吗
Are you going to talk to SIS about Parker?
我没法吃点三明治面包就得到高潮和安宁
I can't sandwich toast to climaxes and peace
因为你在策划一场战争
while you plot a war.
与此同时会发生什么
And what happens in the meantime?
通过保持沉默
By remaining silent,
你让这个危险的女人待在这里
you let this... clearly dangerous woman stay here.
她用不了多久就会再去伤害别人
How long before she hurts someone else?
伤害你的人
One of your girls?
你乖乖吃饭  我唱歌给你听啊
You eat and I sing like a canary, huh?
我们一起放弃原则
We abandon our principles together.
你们是在温室找到她的吗
You found her out by the greenhouse?
她在那地方干什么呢
What was she doing out there?
我不记得把锁美人带到那里去过啊
I do not remember taking Lady Locksley out there.
我不记得
I do not!
她很有可能被动过手脚了
Now, it is quite possible that she has been interfered with.
你能告诉我们在事件发生时  你在哪里吗
Can you tell us where you were at the time the incident took place?
我不知道  事件是什么时候发生的
I don't know. When did the incident take place?
我们不确定  只掌握了时间段
We're not sure. We have a window.
你的锁怎么会出现在温室旁边的院子里
How did your lock end up in the yard by the greenhouse?
我们不确定  只掌握了时间段
We're not sure. We have a window.
-"我们"是谁  -谁
- Who's we? - Who?
沃伦小姐  你在精神病区待过很久
Miss Warren, you've spent your fair share of time in Psych.
你有暴力行为史
You have a history of violent outbursts.
涉及犯人沃特斯通的事件
The incident with inmate Waterstone
你打断了她的锁骨
in which you broke her collarbone.
木工店"意外"背后的事件
The circumstances behind the "accident" in the woodshop.
多次殴打
Several assaults.
在一次事件中你脱光了所有衣服
An episode in which you removed all of your clothes and...
我的治疗师说
Uh, uh, my therapist says,
"昨日已成历史  明日仍是未知"
"Yesterday is history, tomorrow is a mystery."
我们听说帕克女士
We understand there was some bad blood
和瑞泽尼科夫女士不和
between Miss Parker and Mrs. Reznikov.
我们进一步听说
We further understand that
你和帕克女士关系很亲密
you and Miss Parker have a close relationship?
对  维和我很亲密  没错
Yeah, Vee and I are close. That's right.
你觉得是她打了瑞泽尼科夫女士吗
Do you think she slocked Mrs. Reznikov?
没有  维没动手
No. No, no. Vee doesn't do that.
她是老板  我是小弟
She's the brains, I'm the muscle.
你是小弟
You're the muscle?
你是碰巧出现在温室吗
You happen to flex in the greenhouse?
-也许  -也许
- Maybe. - Maybe?
本来说"没有"  现在变成了"可能"
So we've gone from "no" to "maybe"?
没有
No.
No?
有
Yes.
Yes?
我糊涂了
Look... I'm feeling confused.
你有什么想告诉我们的吗
Is there something you'd like to tell us?
没有
No.
有  没有  有  没有  没有
Yes. No. Yes. No. No!
有  没有  有  没有
Yes! No! Yes! No.
等等  没有  有  没有  有
Wait, no, yes, no, yes,
苏珊娜・沃伦  头号疑犯
没有  没有  有  没有
no, no, yes, no.
没有  有  没有  没有  没有
No, no, no. Yes. No. No. No, no, no.
有有有  没有没有没有
Yes. Yes, yes, yes. No, no, no...
我小的时候
You know, when I was a kid,
曾经以为收音机里有小人
I used to think that there were people in the radio.
有一群非常小的人爬进去
Like, these little itty-bitty people that climbed in
演奏他们的小乐器
and played on their mini instruments
朝着小麦克风唱歌
and sang into their tiny microphones!
真蠢
That's stupid.
我曾经给我的娃娃缠上透明胶带
I used to put Scotch Tape around my dolls
这样我就知道在我睡觉的时候它们动了没有
so I'd know if they moved when I was sleeping.
它们从没动过
They never did.
但我总是好奇  它们是否足够聪明
But I always wondered if they were smart enough
能回到原位  把胶带重新贴上
to go back to their exact positions and put the tape back on
这样我就不会察觉
so I wouldn't know.
你们看过那部电影吗
Hey, did you ever see that movie,
里面有个牛仔
the one where there's the cowboy
他是城堡之王
and he's, like, the king of the castle
然后出现了一位宇航员  他想占领城堡
and then this astronaut shows up and he tries to take over
所以牛仔想杀了他
and so the cowboy attempts to murder him,
但结果
but instead
宇航员被一个邪恶的死变态绑架了
the astronaut is taken hostage by, like, this evil psychopath
牛仔必须营救他
and the cowboy has to rescue him
然后他们成为了非常好的朋友
and then they end up becoming really good friends?
是《玩具总动员》吗
Toy Story?
天啊  《玩具总动员》  就是这部
Oh, my God! Toy Story! That's it, that's it.
我爱死那部电影了
I love that movie. Oh!
你的世界观真够扭曲的  孩子
You got one fucked-up perspective on the world, kid.
是啊  经常有人这么说我
Yeah, I hear that a lot.
这大概就是我进监狱的原因
I guess that's why I gotta be locked up.
不
No...
这是你伟大的原因
that's what makes you great.
谢谢你  罗莎
Thanks, Rosa.
亲爱的妈妈  我会想你的  但我必须走了
爱你的海洛因
你想过杰斯和碧昂丝上床的事吗
Hey, you ever think about Jay-Z and Beyonce Fucking?
我想过  甚至比我自慰的次数还多
'Cause I do. Like, more than I do myself, even.
难道你不觉得这很奇怪吗
You don't think that's weird?
谁来过
Who's been in here?
如果你不会算数  我来告诉你
Yo... in case math ain't your jam,
我起码比你重五十磅
you know I got, like, 50 pounds on you, easy!
到底谁他妈来过了
Who the fuck has been in here?
我不知道
I don't know, man.
I don't know.
该死  操
Damn. Fuck.
这是一首关于修女的小曲
This is a little song about the nuns
比匈奴人还要凶猛  卑鄙
Fiercer, meaner, crueler
残忍  粗鲁
Ruder than the Huns
原以为我已摆脱她们
I am forced to babysit them
但却被迫守着她们
When I thought that I had quit them
我真希望她们全都滚蛋
Oh, I kind of hope that they all get the runs
她已经不是修女了
You know, she's not even a nun anymore?
在我们看来  她依然是耶稣的妻子
The way we see it, she's still married to Jesus.
我们是天主教徒  不准离婚
We're Catholics. No divorce.
这是一首关于我父母的歌
This is a song about my mom and dad
以及他们本应离婚的故事
And the divorce that they should have had
天啊
Oh, jeez.
你看来伤的不轻  红妈
You look rough, Red.
是啊
Yeah, well...
把锁装进袜子里  不断地砸头
repeated shots to the head with a lock in a sock
就会达到这种效果
will do that to a person.
谢谢你来看我
Thank you for coming to see me.
但是你让我来的
But you asked.
所以
So...
特别调查处觉得他们都搞清楚了
SIS... thinks they got it figured out.
他们认为是疯眼婆干的
They're pinning everything on Crazy Eye...
沃伦
On Warren.
他们算是让她认了罪
They got some kind of half confession out of her,
这对他们来说就足够了
and that's good enough for them.
他们想回家
They wanna go home.
红妈有事情想告诉你
Red has something she wants to tell you.
我自己能说话  谢谢你  饿肚子的修女
I can speak for myself. Thank you, hungry nun.
说吧
So...
海利
Healy...
你得让特别调查处再来一趟
you have to bring SIS back in here.
你已经做过口供了
You've already made your statement.
我说了  特别调查处觉得他们抓到凶手了
Like I said, SIS thinks they have their gal.
你知道不是她干的
You know she didn't do it.
我想做正确的事  海利
I'm trying to do the right thing here, Healy.
帮帮我
Help me.
我毫不知情
I... I don't know anything.
你想让疯婆子为真正的祸害顶罪吗
You'd let the crazy one take the hit for the real evil?
你的斗志呢  海利
Where's your fight, Healy?
你以前是关心犯人的
You used to care.
他们第一次来问话的时候  你的良心哪去了
Where was your conscience when they were in here the first time?
被她对司法系统的不信任所掩埋了
It was buried under her mistrust for the system...
但她现在试图改正
but she's trying to do right.
但你知道在这种地方试图做一件事会怎样吗
Yeah... well, you know what you get when you try around here?
徒劳无功
Not much.
祝你过得愉快
Have a nice day.
你照顾好自己吧
You take care of yourself, okay?
西斯内罗斯女士
Miss Cisneros.
你好
Hello.
如果你想等她的话
There's a chair outside in the hallway
外面走廊上有椅子
if you'd like to wait there.
我得留下  这是政策
I gotta stay. It's policy.
我当然理解
I understand, of course...
但我想跟我的病人单独相处一会
but I would appreciate a few moments alone with my patient.
我只是在做好本职工作而已
I'm just doing my job.
没关系  医生
It's all right, Doc.
我习惯了
I'm used to it.
好吧
Fine.
西斯内罗斯女士  我们已经收到了你的结果
Miss Cisneros, we've received your results.
我快死了  我知道
I'm dying, I know.
是的  没错
Well... yes, that's true.
-但是  -医生
- But... - Look, Doc...
别跟我瞎扯些什么...
I don't need any bullshit about...
百分比  肿瘤尺寸  癌症几期
percentages or millimeters or stages.
拜托你跟我说话的时候  把我当做...
Do me a favor and talk to me like you would if...
你爱的人
I was a person you loved.
化疗不起作用
The chemo's not working.
这次癌症具有侵袭性
This cancer is aggressive.
我还能活多久
How long I got?
三至六周
Three to six weeks, I'd say.
谢谢
Thank you.
你听到了吗  宝贝
You hear that, my love?
妈咪不会走远了
Mommy's not going far away.
她就留在这里
She's staying right here.
这样我们就见到她
So we can see her...
亲亲她
kiss her...
告诉她我们过得怎么样
and tell her all about how our day was...
我们读了《周五动物园》那本书
and how we read that book Fraidyzoo...
还有你的尿布漏得爸爸满裤子都是
and how your diaper leaked all over Daddy's pants.
没错
That's right.
我们很激动  对吧  宝贝
We're very excited, right, baby?
我们非常激动
We are so excited.
对吧
Aren't we?
是啊
Yeah.
你恨我们吗
Do you hate us?
拜托你说不恨我们
Please tell us you don't hate us...
因为你依然是我的好朋友
because you're still my best friend
我的女性朋友不多
and I don't have a lot of women friends,
我爱你
and I love you,
我无法想象如果失去你这个朋友会怎样
and I can't imagine a world where you're not my friend.
我们想要你的祝福
We want your blessing.
你耍我呢
You're kidding me, right?
你背叛了我
You did cheat on me.
但这不意味着我不会难过啊
That doesn't mean I don't get to have feelings.
要是我的乳头闻起来也像杏仁蛋白软糖多好
If only my nipples smelled like marzipan.
你告诉他了
You told him that?
老天啊
Oh, Jesus...
他没必要知道艾丽克斯的乳头闻起来什么味
He didn't need to know what Alex's nipples smelled like.
奇怪的是  这件事让他开心了一会
It weirdly made him feel better for a minute.
去死吧
Fuck you.
你们两个都去死吧
Fuck both of you.
你说得对
You're right.
她说得对
She's right. Ugh...
这太疯狂了
This is so insane.
实在对不起  我们不该来的
I'm so sorry. We shouldn't have come.
不
No, no.
我们讨论过这件事了  这样合乎情理
We talked about this. It makes sense.
-小帕  -住嘴
- Pipes... - Stop it.
好吧
Fine.
但我们现实点看待这件事吧
But let's be realistic about this.
我们俩都认识你很久了
We both have known you a really long time.
你又不可能突然从我们的生活中消失
It's not like you're suddenly gonna disappear out of our lives.
我们也不希望那样
That's... that's not what we want at least.
我们  天啊
We? Oh, God...
天呐  真恶心
Oh, God, gross.
我们能成熟对待这件事吗
Can we be adults about this, please?
行啊
Sure.
好呀
Okay.
我们成熟一点
Let's be adults.
我们把话都摊到台面上说
Let's get this all out on the table...
好把事情搞清楚
just so that we're clear, okay?
我们分手之后
The first person...
你睡的第一个女人
that you fuck... after we break up...
是我闺蜜
is my best friend.
我已婚的...
My married...
闺蜜
best friend.
而你
And you...
刚刚生了孩子
you have a newborn.
当时你的阴道那么松  适合做爱吗
I mean, was your vagina even fuckable at that point
还是你只是把乳汁喷得他浑身都是
or were you just squirting your milk all over him?
然后你们做了最糟糕的一件事
And then you did the worst thing.
你们决定...
You decided...
相爱了
to fall in love.
然后你们就想  "有个主意不错呢
And then you thought, "You know what'd be a great idea?
我们去监狱探视帕波吧
Let's go visit... Piper in prison...
因为她就住在那里
because that's where she lives...
因为她现在过得很好
because things are going so great for her,
我们坐在她对面
and let's sit across from her...
让她祝福我们吧
and ask for her blessing...
这样我们就能感觉
so that we can walk away... feeling absolved
我们所做的操蛋决定都可以得到赦免了"
of all of the fucked-up choices that we have made."
你说得对
You're right.
这事很操蛋
It's fucked up.
我知道这点  莱瑞也知道
I know that. Larry knows that.
但我们不是决定彼此相爱的  帕波
But we didn't decide to love each other, Piper.
一切都猝不及防
It just happened.
爱情就是这个样子
The way love does.
而且我的阴道很快就反弹回来了
And my vagina bounced back really fast.
海利先生
Mr. Healy.
你觉得我的新发型如何
What do you think?
我更喜欢长发
I prefer long hair.
但这是反传统文化啊
Hey, but it's counter-culture.
你知道这个词是什么意思吗
Do you even know what that means?
不太懂
Not really.
但我觉得这不重要
But I don't really think it matters...
只要你比别人更大声地说出自己的观点就行
as long as you say your opinion louder than everybody else's.
-祝你过得愉快  德盖特  -等一下
- Have a good one, Doggett. - Hold on.
等等  我想跟你谈谈
Wait! I wanna talk to you.
我想为安全地带补开一堂课
I wanna do a make-up class for Safe Place, all right?
我这周空闲时间比较多
I have a lot of free time this week.
你昨天好像很忙嘛
You seemed to be pretty busy yesterday.
所以你才绷着个脸吗
Is that why you're all sourpussed?
你不开心是因为我不止你一个朋友吗
You sad 'cause I have another friend besides you?
我还以为我们价值观相同
I thought we had the same values.
我们的价值观确实相同
We do have the same values.
我们都喜欢表达自己的想法
We like to express ourselves,
我们都喜欢友善待人  对吧
and we like to be kind to people, right?
海利先生  因为你  我交了个新朋友
I mean, because of you, Mr. Healy, I made a new friend,
我本来永远也不会跟她打交道  你知道这点
somebody that I would've never talked to, and you know it.
这多了不起啊
I mean, now, is that something else or what?
敢再碰我一下  你就有麻烦了
Touch me again and we're gonna have a problem.
明白吗
Do you understand?
听着
All right, listen.
你不用说出来  好吗
You don't gotta talk, okay?
我知道你对男人婆们看不顺眼
I know you got issues with the butchies,
你也没什么错
and you're not that far off the mark.
我昨天没去小组聚会
And I know you're pissed off at me
我知道你为此生我的气
that I didn't make it to group.
对不起  但我想告诉你件事
Sorry, but I want you to know something.
我会永远对你心怀感激
I am forever grateful to you.
因为我这辈子  只有你一个人
'Cause you're the only person... in my whole life that's...
肯花时间跟我聊天
ever taken the time to talk to me.
看起来
And it just seems like...
你很擅长这份工作  也很关心犯人
you're really good at what you do and that you really care.
我绝不会给她手交  也不会让她给我手交
And I will never finger her and I will never let her finger me.
这都是驱逐恶灵的步骤
This is all part of making the evil go away.
好的
Okay.
还有最后一步
And the final step.
跟我讲讲事情经过
Why don't you tell me what happened?
我打了她
I hit her...
一直打
and hit her...
and hit her.
你为何要这么做
Why did you do that?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
你是不记得打了她
You don't remember doing it...
还是不记得为什么打她
or you don't remember why?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
你袭击红妈了吗
Did you attack Red?
维说我干了
Vee said I did.
那两个来问话的男人也说我干了
Those men who were here said I did.
难道我不该相信他们吗
Shouldn't I believe 'em?
不
No.
你应该知道自己干了什么
You should know what you did.
我记不得了
I can't remember!
我以为我当时在仓库里拖地
Now, I thought I was... mopping in the warehouse.
结果却在温室里打人
Turns out, I was slocking in the greenhouse.
我一定是把"仓库"和"温室"
I must... you know, I must've mixed up
或者"拖地"和"打人"给搞混了
"ware" and "green" or "mop" and "slock."
这是有可能的
That could happen...
对吧
right?
可能性很小
It's very unlikely.
是啊
Yes.
可我能相信谁呢
But who can I trust?
你自己
Yourself.
不行
No.
我不靠谱
I'm unreliable.
红妈会好起来吗
Is Red gonna be okay?
我一直很喜欢她
I always liked her.
虽说她很可怕
She's... scary,
但她的头发就像
but... her hair is like
《今年没有圣诞老人》里的高温先生一样
the Heat Miser in that Christmas special...
你不觉得吗
don't you think?
她是绿色圣诞夫人
She's, uh... Mrs. Green Christmas.
她是太阳夫人
She's Mrs. Sun.
是啊
Yeah.
那么
So...
他们要怎么处理我
what's gonna happen to me now?
真好  你在收拾东西
Oh, good, you're packing up.
我刚收到消息说我要正式接手你的工作了
I just got word that I am officially taking over your job.
长期接手还是在他们找到像样的人选之前过渡一下
Permanently or interim till they find someone real?
他给了你一段试用期对吧
He's giving you a trial run, isn't he?
48小时还是72小时
What is it, 48 hours, 72?
你能坚持几天时间不搞砸吗  这份工作很有挑战性
Can you not fuck up for a few days? There's a real challenge.
与此同时
Meanwhile...
你这个翘臀妞被开除了
your shapely ass is canned
而我的屁股会坐在那把椅子上
while mine is sitting in that chair.
我没被开除  我辞职了
I wasn't canned. I resigned.
我离开的时候  典狱长赞扬了
I am leaving with a commendation from the warden
我对这座监狱的热忱服务
about my dedicated service to this institution,
还发表了一篇新闻稿表示
and a press release about
他很遗憾我决定投身政治
how sad he is that I have decided to devote myself to politics
并有可能做全职母亲
and possibly motherhood full-time.
你他妈是怎么做到这些的
How the fuck do you do that?
你怎么总能逃脱惩罚
How do you keep getting away with shit?
我什么也没逃脱
I'm not getting away with anything.
典狱长只是够聪明
The warden is simply smart enough
知道他不想手握一桩丑闻
to realize he doesn't want a scandal on his hands
而且不想成为我老公的政治敌人
and he doesn't wanna make a political enemy of my husband.
你的基佬老公吗
Your gay husband?
你的乐队烂透了
Your band sucks.
你的口活烂透了
Your blowjobs suck.
我很擅长这份工作  乔
I was good at my job, Joe.
情况很复杂  但我做得不错
It was complicated but I made it work.
我们来看看你干得怎么样
Let's see how you do.
我认为  首先
Well, I figure, for starters,
如果我不挪用公款  不撒谎  不渎职
if I simply don't embezzle and lie and neglect...
省省吧  姐累了  要离开这里了
Oh, save it. I'm tired and I'm leaving.
祝你的高尚节操好运吧
Good luck with your noble intentions.
这地方很快就能让你节操掉一地
This place'll beat 'em out of you quick.
阿曼达有个理论
Well, Amanda has a theory that
我坐牢全是因为贫穷的恶性循环
it's all because of the cycle of poverty
学校太烂  吃的是政府奶酪
and the bad schools and the government cheese
还因为我是黑人  我妈嗑药
and because I'm brown and my mom was on crack.
但我觉得是因为...
But I think it's because...
我做事太混蛋了
I was just being an asshole.
你不是说了不提伤感的事吗
I thought you said no mushy shit.
对不起  珀比  实在抱歉
I'm sorry, P. I really am.
麦肯锡认为这是被压抑的失望所致
Yeah, well... Mackenzie thinks it's repressed frustration
因为你从没去过巴黎
'cause you ain't never been to Paris.
可能也有这个原因
It's probably that, too.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
《异乡人》
Outlander.
-你读过这本书吗  -没有
- You ever read this? - Nah.
有个姑娘穿越时空回到苏格兰
Lady travels back in time to Scotland and some shit,
跟一个超性感的亡命之徒勾搭上了
hooks up with this big sexy outlaw type
他们就日夜不停地疯狂做爱啊
and they be gettin' it day in and day out.
太火辣了
Yo, it's hot!
但那个男人是白皮肤红头发
But the dude's, like... pale with red hair.
不是我的菜
Not my thing.
但如果我能穿越时空  我会回到非洲
But if I go back in time, I go back to Africa.
我要找一位长着巨根的努比亚国王
I find me a Nubian king with a Nubian thing.
我小的时候
Yo, look, when I was a kid,
我父母租了《回到未来》这部电影
my parents rented that movie Back to the Future.
我深信不疑
I was mad convinced.
所以每次出家门
So, like, every time I left the house,
我的背包里都装满了东西  以防我会穿越时空
my backpack was full of stuff just in case I went back in time.
我都准备好了等时光机来接我
I was all ready for my DeLorean...
但它从没来过
but it never came.
瞧啊  珀比
Yo, P.
你们他妈想干什么
The fuck do y'all want, man?
冷静  该死的图书馆忍者  我们是来讲和的
Chill, you fuckin' book ninja. We come in peace.
是真的  这件事闹得太大了
For real. This shit's gone too far.
你们发现得有点晚啊
Yeah, well, took you fucking long enough to notice.
那个贱人一直追着我问
That bitch went crazy on my ass.
"我那玩意呢  我那玩意呢"  她大爆发了
"Where's my shit? Where's my shit?" She cracked wide open.
-等等  什么玩意  她那破玩意吗  -对
- Wait. What shit? Her shit shit? - Mmm-hmm.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
不见了
Went missing, yeah.
她发了疯
She's out of her mind.
我猜她接下来就会冲你们来了
Guessing she'll be coming after y'all next.
但我们手上没有她的玩意
Yo, but we ain't got her shit.
她说要为这事干掉所有人
She talkin' about takin' everybody out for it.
我不在乎货在不在你们手上
Look, I don't care if y'all got it or not.
我只想知道
I just wanna know
我会不会在睡着的时候被打
I'm not getting slocked in my bed
或在上大号的时候被捅
or shanked on the dooker.
如果她在怀疑你们所有人
Yo, if she's suspecting y'all,
就说明她手里面没有人了
then that means she ain't got no people no more...
除了疯眼婆
except Crazy Eyes.
是啊  疯眼婆接受了特别调查处的问话
Mmm-mmm, Crazy Eyes be out with SIS
把打红妈的事揽到了自己头上
takin' the fall for doin' Red.
维让那个疯女人以为是自己干的
Vee got that noodle-brain convinced she did it.
我们也煽风点火了
We kind of helped with that, too.
希望你能坦然地面对你的神
I hope you right with your God with that one.
我们已经够内疚了  不需要你来教育我们
Hey, don't make us try and feel badder than we already do.
你们也跟过维
Y'all was with Vee, too.
你们也做过不厚道的事
Y'all was doing sketchy shit, too.
她一定为那些毒品丧失理智了吧
She must really be losin' it over them drugs, huh?
疯了
Lost it.
也许我们能弥补这件事
Yo, maybe we can make this right.
维手底下没有人  我们又是一条心
I mean... Vee got no one. We all talkin'.
-所以我们要突袭她吗  -别闹
- So we jump her? Pow, pow, pow! - Yo, don't!
我入伙
I'm in.
不  我觉得我们不必动手
No... I don't think we need to do all that.
好了  我采取行动了
Okay... I made an effort.
现在轮到你了
It's your turn.
吃点东西吧
Eat something.
好吧
Fine.
好了  修女
Okay, Sister.
我叫停了你的转狱
I've stopped your transfer.
我之前要被转狱吗
I was being transferred?
没错  你  查普曼  还有其他一些人
That's right. You, Chapman and a bunch of others.
菲格原本要把你们都送到弗吉尼亚去
Fig was having you all sent to Virginia.
我给摆平了  你们都可以留下了
I just took care of it. You're all staying here.
你难道不高兴吗
Aren't you glad?
这...
Well, it...
对于一件我都不知情的事情
it's hard to be emotionally invested in something
很难投入感情
I didn't know was happening,
不过我猜这是个好消息
but... yes, I... I suppose that's good news.
很好
Good.
我帮了你一个忙
I've done you a solid.
现在你能帮我个忙吗
Now would you do something for me?
吃点东西
Eat something.
别吃东西  英格尔斯  与权势抗争到底
Don't eat a thing, Ingalls. Fight the power.
红妈  你在帮倒忙
Red, you're not helping.
听着
Look...
菲格出局了
Fig is out.
我当权了
I'm in.
给我个胜局
Give me a win here.
让我向政府证明我能掌控局势
Let me show the administration I can handle situations.
我想有所作为  修女
I wanna make a difference, Sister.
你愿意帮我吗
Would you do that for me?
给
Here...
我给你带了个玛芬蛋糕
I brought you a muffin.
吃吧
Go ahead.
吃吧  咬一口
Go ahead... take a bite.
今天就到此为止
We'll call it a day.
好的
Yeah.
吃吧
Go ahead.
真棒  好极了
Excellent. All right.
好姑娘
Attagirl.
你现在能让你的修女们解散了吗
Now would you mind calling off your nuns?
卢斯奇克
Luschek.
我有件事要问你
Need to ask you something.
-你可以网购  -什么
- You can buy it on the Internet. - What?
不管你在找什么
Whatever you're looking for.
我可以帮你想想该输什么搜索关键字
I guess I could help you with what words to type in.
会涉及我不想知道的隐私吗
Do I wanna know that much about you?
你他妈这是什么意思
What the fuck are you talking about?
我要问问你沃伦的情况
I need to ask you about Warren.
谁
Who?
疯眼婆
Crazy Eyes.
在红妈被打的时候
You might've seen her in electrical
你可能在配电区见过她
around the time Red got slocked.
打扫卫生  拖地板之类的
Cleaning up, sweeping the floor, something like that.
我可能见过
I, uh... might have.
太棒了
Well, that's great.
我需要一份显示有
I need an interdepartmental work order
她向你报告的具体时间的跨部门工作单
showing the specific time that she reported to you.
那么
And, uh...
我为你撒谎  你就欠了我个大人情  对吧
you would owe me a big one for lying for you, right?
以后再决定怎么报答我
You know, something to be determined at a later date?
当然
Sure.
好吧
Fine.
表格在这里
Here's the form.
这下有意思了
This is gonna be fun.
转过去
Turn around.
谢谢你  卢斯奇克
Thanks, Luschek.
美味
Hey, Taystee.
我的姑娘还好吗
How's my girl?
谁  我吗
Who? Me?
得了吧
Come on, now.
我之前必须教训你一下  但一切都过去了
I had to teach you a little lesson, but... the time out is over.
回来吧
Come on back.
跟妈妈一起玩耍
Play with Mama.
我还是继续待在角落吧
I think I'll stay in the corner.
待在角落的时候  朝四周看看
And while you in that corner, look around.
你不会碰巧藏了一大盒
You wouldn't happen to be hiding a big box of something
不属于你的东西吧
that's not yours, would you?
我没拿你的破玩意
I didn't take your shit.
但你知道是谁干的
But you know who did!
二位
Hey, guys.
出什么事了
What's going on?
这不关你的事
This... does not concern you.
美味  我们已经认识够久了
Taystee, we've been together long enough.
不需要我来提醒你
I don't have to remind you...
如果有人越界会是什么下场
what happens when someone oversteps.
你是说像RJ一样吗
You mean like RJ?
对
Yes.
像RJ一样
Like RJ.
你本来十年前就该死了
You'd be 10 years dead now.
你本来不过是埋在旷野里六英尺深的
You'd be just another anonymous black child
又一个无名的黑人孩子
buried six deep in a county field.
妈妈们的问题在于
Here's the thing about mamas.
只有在她们有孩子的时候才是妈妈
They're only mamas as long as they got kids.
没了孩子  她们又是什么
Without 'em, what are they?
啥也不是
Uh... nothing.
你手里得有人才行
You got to have people.
尤其是在这里  你必须有
Especially in here, you just got to.
否则  你就会发现自己四面楚歌
Otherwise, you find yourself vulnerable to all sorts of shit.
好多锁
Lots of locks.
好多袜子
Lots of socks.
你们要把我撵出去吗
You're turning me out?
去你们的
Fuck you.
你们以为我活不下去吗
You think I can't survive?
我会找到新家的
I will find a new family.
你当然能
'Course you will.
只要有像你这样的神经病
As long as there's psychos like you,
就总有人愿意跟随
there's always people willing to follow.
你在重刑监狱一定会找到各种新跟班
Yeah, I'm sure you'll find all sorts of new suckers over at max.
是啊
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
我们为苏珊娜感到非常难过
See, we feel real bad about Suzanne.
所以我们要...  那个词叫来着
So we about to... What's that... what's that word?
撤回证词
Recant.
对  我们要宣布撤回证词
Yeah, we about to recant our shit.
你知道是谁编造出了"永不告密"的破规定吗
Yeah, you know who made up that "Never snitch" bullshit?
大概是那些活该被告密的人
People who probably deserved to be snitched on.
美味
Taystee.
我的美味姑娘
My Taystee Girl.
你伤透了我的心
You break my heart.
可能吧
Might be true...
如果你还有心的话
if you had one.
知道我在想什么吗
Hey, you know what I was thinking?
你看过《玩具总动员2》吗
You ever seen Toy Story 2?
虽说很难相信
You know, it's hard to believe,
但它比第一部还好看
but it's better than the first one.
虽说续集从来没法超越第一部
And even though sequels never are...
但这一部  是个例外
this? This is the exception to the rule.
所以我在想  或许我们可以让他们下周放这部片子
So, I was thinking, maybe we could get them to play it next week.
难道不是很棒吗
Wouldn't that be good, huh?
她完了
She's done.
要死翘翘了
Done, done.
只能再活几周  这是医生说的
Only has a few more weeks. That's what the doc said.
天啊  死在监狱里太倒霉了  对吧
Man... it's real fucked up to die in prison, right?
虽说死本身就很倒霉
I mean, it's fucked up to die, period, but...
但死在监狱里
this is really, I mean...
真心倒霉
it's fucked up.
我好喜欢这首歌
Man, I love this one.
查普曼
Chapman.
什么事
Yeah?
你说得对
You were right, you know?
我刚进来的时候你对我说的话
What you said to me when I first got here.
我说了什么
What did I say?
你让我找个老婆
You told me to find a wife...
一个照顾我的人
someone to look out for me.
我应该听你的话
I should've listened.
我那是耍你玩呢
Yeah, I was fucking with you.
我知道
I know.
但你说得对
But you were right.
天呐  这是我待过最孤独的地方
God, this is the loneliest place I've ever been
我还曾在树上独自住过八个月呢
and I lived alone in a tree for eight months.
在这里你基本上要靠自己
Yeah, you're pretty much on your own in here.
这样很没劲
It sucks.
而且没人能理解你
And no one understands.
梅朵问我  她能不能给我寄爱心包裹
Like, Meadow asked if she could send me a care package.
她以为这里是夏令营
She thinks this is camp.
但这里不是  这里糟透了
But it's not. It's... awful.
我觉得我出去之后就会像是变了个人
I don't think I'm gonna be the same when I get out.
或许那没关系
Maybe that's okay.
这样一点都不好
It's not fucking okay.
我知道
I know.
沃伦小姐
Miss Warren.
Miss Warren!
当局很快会过来
The authorities will be here soon
把你转移到另一家监狱
to transfer you to another facility
等待这次指控的审讯
to await trial on this charge.
谢谢你的配合
Thank you for your cooperation.
要说"谢谢"  要说"请"
Oh! "We say 'thank you, ' we say 'please,
打喷嚏时要说"不好意思"
' and 'excuse me, ' when we sneeze.
守规矩就要这样做
That's the way we do what's right.
讲文明又懂礼貌
We have manners. We're polite."
怎么
What?
你想不想回家了
You wanna go home or not, huh?
我今晚要去白马餐厅跟谢丽尔约会
I'm supposed to meet Cheryl at the White Horse tonight.
好吧
Fine.
再见  先生  我说"再见"
Good day, sir. I say, "Good day."
谢谢你  谢谢你
Thank you very much. Thank you very much.
不  谢谢你
No, thank you very much.
不  谢谢你  谢谢你
No, thank you very much. Thank you very, very much.
谢谢你
Thank you very much.
谢谢你  走  再见
Thank you. Go. Bye.
不好意思  我要撤回我的证词
Excuse me, I need to recant my testimony.
我得到了新消息
Hey, hey, I got new information.
-是维・帕克干的  -对
- It was Vee Parker. - Yes.
-是维・帕克干的  -你们得相信我们
- Vee Parker did it. - Yo, you gotta believe us.
虽说疯眼婆是个疯子  所以好像是她干的
It might've seemed like it was Crazy Eyes 'cause that bitch is crazy,
但其实不是她
but it was not her.
对  正义没有得到声张
Yeah, justice is not being served.
女士们  抱歉  我们今天要下班了
Ladies, I'm sorry. We're done for the day.
-不行  -警卫呢
- No! No! - Where is security?
这里有狱警吗
Is there a CO around here?
女士们  我强烈建议你们离开走廊
Ladies, I strongly suggest you clear this hallway.
-就听我们说几句  -是维・帕克干的
- Just listen for one sec! - It was Vee Parker!
等等  等等
Hold up. Hold up.
太好了  海利先生  请控制一下你的犯人
Oh, good, Mr. Healy, please control your inmates.
控制  我们不需要控制
Control? We don't need control.
我这里有张工作单
I have a work order here.
不可能是沃伦干的  她当时在配电区
There's no way Warren could've done it. She was in electrical.
你们得放她走  这案子还没结
You gotta let her go. Case is still open.
妈的
Shit.
你该给谢丽尔打个电话
You should call Cheryl.
对  你该给谢丽尔打电话
Yeah, you should call Cheryl.
"亲爱的  我要晚点回家了"
"Honey, I'm gonna be home late."
天啊
Jesus.
进来
Come in.
欢迎你  约翰
Welcome, John!
你喜欢我的新办公室吗
You like my new office?
喜欢  这里很不错
Yeah, it's, uh... it's very nice.
卡普托先生
Look, Mr. Caputo...
我不能再做缩头乌龟了  我得...
I can't be a pussy anymore. I have to...
站起来  做个男人
stand up and be a man.
不要
Oh, no, don't.
拜托你别告诉我你又搜查了另一间宿舍
Please don't tell me you busted up another dorm.
-我不能...  -达娅的孩子是我的
- I can't... - Daya's baby's mine.
孩子是我的
The baby's mine.
她怀了我的孩子  然后害怕了
I got her pregnant and she got scared,
所以她跟门德斯发生了关系
so she had sex with Mendez
这样我就不必受到责怪
so that I wouldn't get blamed, but...
但我必须站出来  那是我的孩子
I have to step up. It's, uh... it's my child...
-别说了  -那是我的孩子  我的宝宝
- Stop talking. - It's my child. It's my baby.
我说了"别说了"
I said, "Stop talking."
妈蛋
Jesus tits.
这才是我上任的第二天
It's my second day.
不行
I can't.
我不能摊上这样事
I can't... I can't have this.
不行
No.
这件事已经处理完了
This has been dealt with.
可孩子是我的  门德斯被起诉了
But the baby's mine. Mendez is being prosecuted.
因为门德斯干了她
'Cause Mendez fucked her.
我也是
So did I!
不  你没有
No, you didn't.
先生  我干了她
Sir, I... I fucked her.
你爱这个姑娘吗  本尼特
Do you love this girl, Bennett?
爱
I do.
那我建议你别把这事捅出去
Then I suggest you keep your mouth shut
否则我会把你的爱人  利奇菲尔德"公交车"
or I will send your love, the town pump of Litchfield,
送进重刑监狱  让她终日待在牢房里
to a max facility where she will spend her days in a cage
远离你  还有她的母亲和朋友们
away from you and her mother and her friends
直到她生下你的孩子
until she delivers your child
双手双脚都铐在产床上
with her hands and feet cuffed to a bed.
你找我有什么事  本尼特
What do you want, Bennett?
没什么  先生
Nothing, sir.
很好
Good.
这是我的第二天
It's my second day.
我他妈的第二天
My second fucking day.
滚出去
Get out of here.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
一名来自利奇菲尔德联邦监狱的囚犯
An inmate from Litchfield Federal Prison
正试图联系您
is attempting to contact you.
要接听来电  请按1
To accept this call, please press one.
-咱们要接吗  -是帕波
- Should we take that? - It's Piper.
咱们必须接
We have to.
帕波
Piper.
喂  你是一个人吗
Hi, are you alone?
我跟波丽一起在车里  我开了免提
I'm in the car with Polly. You're on speaker.
可不是嘛
Ah! Of course I am.
你想补偿我吗
Listen, do you wanna make it up to me?
那要看你指的是什么事
Depends on what that means.
我需要你帮个忙
I need a favor.
莱瑞  如果你不愿意帮我
And, Larry, if you're not willing to do this...
那么波丽  我要找你帮忙
then, Polly, I'm asking you.
是什么事
What is it?
有个缓刑官叫大卫・克罗克特
There's a probation officer and his name is David Crockett.
跟电影《大卫克罗传》重名
Just like Davy Crockett.
他大概在皇后区缓刑办公室的
He probably works for the federal division
联邦部门工作
of the Queens County probation office.
你们肯定能在网上找到这个办事处
I'm sure that you can find the bureau online.
好
Okay.
我要你打电话告诉他
I need you to call him and tell him...
艾丽克斯・沃斯
that Alex Vause
违反了缓刑规定
is violating her probation
她准备逃走了
and that she is on her way out of town.
这是真的吗
Is that true?
是的
Yes.
这么做的目的是什么
And the purpose of this is what?
莱瑞  我这是在给你机会
Larry, I am giving you the opportunity
毁掉一个你恨的人
to fuck over someone that you hate.
我为什么要那么做
And why would I do that?
那样她就能回去陪你了吗
So she lands back in there with you?
波丽
Polly?
那个办公室叫什么来着
What's the office called, again?
她去哪了
Where is she?
有人看见帕克了吗
Anybody seen Parker?
帕克
Parker?
你不知道你的犯人去哪了吗
You don't know where your inmates are?
有人吗
Hello?
老天
Jesus.
好了
Okay.
那帮毒虫工作的洗衣房
The laundry room where the meth heads work?
你他妈当时在想什么呢
What the fuck were you thinking?
我在想  这个地方够大能装下
I was thinking it's a place big enough to hold it
而且必须暂时放在这里
and it would have to do for now.
好了
All right.
快点  把这些塞进你的裤子里
Oh, come on. Start stuffing these down your pants
回仓库去
and head back to the warehouse.
我去找卡普托  我们引他过去  逮住那个贱人
I'll grab Caputo. We lead him to it and we nail the bitch.
等等
Wait a minute.
你想让我裤子里塞着海洛因
You want me to walk from here to the warehouse
从这走到仓库
with heroin stuffed in my pants?
死也别想
No fucking way.
得了吧  你已经够胖了  没人会发现的
Come on, you're already bulky. No one's gonna notice.
你当初是怎么运过来的
How'd you get it here in the first place?
用洗衣袋  我把它藏在了一堆衣服里
Laundry bag. I hid it in some clothes.
拿着一袋衣服去洗衣房很合乎情理
You know, it makes sense to go to laundry with a bag of clothes.
但拿着一袋衣服去仓库就说不通了
Makes no sense to go to the warehouse with a laundry bag of clothes.
好吧  我有个主意
Yeah, well, here's an idea.
你为何不把毒品挪到那里的其他地方呢
Why didn't you just leave it there in a different spot?
-说真的  -是啊
- Seriously? - Uh-huh.
你知道她把那个地方毁了
You know she tore that place apart.
换做是我  就会把那个地方毁了
If it was me, I would've torn that place apart.
妮琪
You know, Nicky...
万一卡普托不相信那是维的呢
what if Caputo doesn't believe that this is Vee's?
万一他以为是咱们的呢
I mean, what if he thinks it's ours?
或许我们该自己留着
Maybe we should keep it?
-操  -妈的
- Oh, fuck. - Shit!
所有人都趴下了吗
Everybody down?
很好
Good.
出什么事了
What's going on?
帕克失踪了
Parker's missing.
待在这里
Stay here.
出什么事了
What's going on?
有个犯人失踪了
An inmate is missing.
回你们的铺位清点人数
Back to your bunks for count.
好吧
All right.
走吧  孩子  咱们晚点再处理这个
Come on, son. We'll deal with this later.
全体犯人  马上回到你们的铺位清点人数
All inmates, return to your bunks for count immediately.
尼古拉斯
Nichols?
这座监狱正式进入一级防范禁闭
This prison is officially on lockdown.
在接到进一步通知前  请留在你们的铺位
Please remain in your bunks until further notice.
该死  有人跑了
Holy shit, we got a runner.
你们以前遇到过逃犯吗
You ever had a runner before?
没有
No.
很有意思的
Oh, it's fun.
站住别动
Don't take another step!
搞什么飞机
What the fuck?
你找我有事吗
Can I help you?
我不知道你在家
I didn't know you were home.
我他妈不在乎  你不能突然闯进我的公寓
I don't fucking care. You can't just walk into my apartment!
我通常知道这点
Yeah, I know that... usually, but...
但是他让我进来的
he asked me to.
克罗克特先生
Mr. Crockett.
沃斯小姐
Miss Vause.
操
Fuck.
在接到进一步通知前  请留在你们的铺位
And you will remain in your bunks until further notice.
没有例外  别找借口
No exceptions, no excuses.
原地解散
Fall out.
一号宿舍  二号宿舍  三号宿舍
A-Dorm, B-Dorm, C-Dorm,
我们进入了一级防范禁闭
we are on lockdown.
立即返回你们的区域
Return to your area immediately.
你的发质真好  姑娘
You got some good hair, girl.
差不多有特雷・埃利斯・罗斯那种双种族的质地
Almost that Tracee Ellis Ross biracial texture.
差不多
Almost.
不过有点干
It's a little dry, though.
我得给你涂点护发素  或者h个油
I need to get you a co-wash, maybe a hot oil treatment.
-十五  十六  十七  -等等  腿伸直
-... 15, 16, 17... - Oh, wait. No, keep your leg straight.
对  十七  十八
Yeah, 17, 18...
超过十五年了  那个女人是个死疯子
...for, like, over 15 years. That woman was fucking insane.
那就他妈躲着点
Then fuckin' ditched your ass.
可你们要像之前那样羞辱我吗
But you... how y'all gonna diss me like y'all did before?
他妈的
Fuck it.
别死在这里  罗莎小姐  自己找地方死去
Don't die in here, Miss Rosa. Go do it your own way.
我该怎么做
What do I do?
开快点
Go fast.
监狱进入一级防范禁闭了
Prison's on lockdown.
我们得把她送回房间  把你送回...
We need to get her back to rooms and get you back...
-搞什么鬼  -老天爷啊
- What the fuck? - Oh, lord in heaven!
-操操操  -天啊
- Oh, shit. Shit! Shit! - Oh, my God!
罗莎  回来
Rosa, come back here!
你会惹上大麻烦的  罗莎
You're gonna get in big trouble, Rosa!
这警报声是怎么回事
What's going on with the alarms?
对你而言  我们只是在测试系统
As far as you're concerned, we're just testing the system.
再跟我复述一遍你要说什么
Now tell me again what you're gonna say.
"我已决定结束我的绝食抗议"
"I've elected to end my hunger strike."
没错
That's right.
我感觉像是个托儿
I feel like a shill.
牺牲小我  英格尔斯  想想所带来的好处
Greater good, Ingalls. Eye on the prize.
继续
Go on.
"感谢你们的努力  我的姊妹们
"Thanks to the efforts of you, my sisters,
管理部门已经听到了我们的强烈抗议
the administration has heard our outcry
并在采取措施解决我们的诉求"
and is taking steps to address our complaints."
"从任命乔・卡普托担任副典狱长开始"
"Beginning with the appointment of Assistant Warden Joe Caputo."
这他妈是怎么回事
What the fuck?
奥尼尔  让修女们散开
O'Neill, scatter the nuns!
快跑  修女们  跑啊
Run, nuns! Run!
快跑
Run!
操
Oh, fuck!
该阻塞由道路施工造成
And that backup is due to road work
这次施工大概要持续到明晚
that's going to be going on probably until tomorrow night.
如果您正向东行驶在邓肯...
Now if you're traveling eastbound on Duncan...
那娘们总是那么粗鲁
Always so rude, that one.